Guide to the American Federation of Musicians, Local 802 Records WAG.038
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: General Files, 1922-2010
  Series V: General Files, 1922-2010 includes contracts, legal files, and an almost complete run of Local 802 directories and constitutions and by-laws.
  - Collective Bargaining Agreements: Steady Engagement Hotel Users of Music, 1970s-1980s (Box 67)
  - Collective Bargaining Agreements: Westbury Music Fair; Legal Files (mostly National Labor Relations Board and New York State Labor Relations Board), 1960s-1980s (Box 68)
  - Legal Files (mostly National Labor Relations Board and New York State Labor Relations Board); Theatre Committee Files; and Symphony Orchestra Background Files, 1960s-early 1990s (Box 69)
  - Symphony Orchestra Background Files, Restructuring and Strategic Planning, Arbitration and Legal Files relating to Livent (Toronto), and List of Recording Contracts [?], early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 70)
  - National Labor Relations Board Cases and Television and Videotape Negotiations, 1970s-1980s (Box 71)
  - Bylaws (1981-2000), Steven Scott Enterprises, Recording Musicians Association (RMA) Files relating to the Low Budget Phonograph Agreement, and New York City Ballet (Box 72)
  - Reel-to-reel Audiotapes of Meetings [?], circa 1950s (Box 72)
  - National Labor Relations Board Cases and MEMBERS Party Files, 1970s-early 1990s (Box 73)
  - MEMBERS Party Files and Vice-President Mary Landolfi's Files (mostly on orchestras), early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 74)
  - Vice-President Mary Landolfi's Files (mostly on orchestras), early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 75)
  - Vice-President Mary Landolfi's Files (mostly on orchestras) and Files on Contracts and Agreements from Unknown Office, early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 76)
  - China United Restaurant Contract, McGraw-Hill Office, and Gellman and Rosoff Cases, 1969-early 1990s (Box 114)
  - Senior Musicians Association (includes photographs), 1970s-1990s (Box 115)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1932-1941 (Box 119)
  - New York Philharmonic File, 1953 (Box 119)
  - Local 802 Directories, 1922-1950 (Box 118)
  - Local 802 Directories, 1951-2008 (Box 128)
  - Lists of American Federation of Musicians Locals, 1993-2010 (Box 128)
  - American Federation of Musicians Constitutions and Bylaws, 1926-2005 (Box 128)
  - Local 802 Constitutions and Bylaws, 1921-1955 (Box 128)
  - Local 802 Constitutions and Bylaws, 1957-1983 (Box 129)
  - Agreements, 1975-1984 (Box 129)
  - Directories, Constitutions, and Price Lists from Locals 4, 6, 47, 72, 76, 238, 310 (802's predecessor) 402, 526, 655 and Related Organizations, 1921-1995 (Box 129)
  - Price Lists and Other Local 802 Pamphlets (Box 129)
  - Restructure Committee, 1990s (Box 130)
  - National Convention, 1995-2003 (Box 130)
  - 1938 Election and Committee of Fifteen Material (sent by David B. Freed), 1934-1990 (Box 130)
  - Regular Membership Meetings Minutes, 1922-1965 (Film R-7438, Reel 79)
  - Medical Board Minutes, 1936-1940 (Film R-7438, Reel 79)
  - Music Festival Dance Jubliee program, 1939 (Box Shared Tamiment 049, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Organizing Department Files, 1980s-mid 2000s
  Series VI: Organizing Department Files, 1980s-mid 2000s consists mostly of the records of the Organizing Department's records of the 1980s-1990s under Organizing Director Marvin Moschel.
  - Subject Files: A-M, mid 1980s (Box 77)
  - Joe Eisman's Files, late 1990s-mid 2000s (Box 78)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files: A-C (mostly club date), early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 79)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files: C-F (mostly club date), early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 80)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files: G-M, early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 81)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files: W, early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 82)
  - Subject Files A-Z, mid 1990s-late 1990s (Box 82)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files, 1980s (Box 82)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files, 1980s (Box 83)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files (mostly hotel negotiations), early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 83)
  - Marvin Moschel's Files, early 1990s-mid 1990s (Box 84)
  - Subject Files: P-T, mid 1980s-early 2000s (Box 84)
  - Subject Files: U-Z, mid 1980s-early 2000s (Box 85)
  - Organizing Campaigns, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 85)
- Series VII: Public Relations and Political Action Office Files, late 1970s-2000
  Series VII: Public Relations and Political Action Office Files, late 1970s-2000 contains significant material on the Local 802 supported reform of New York City's cabaret law, as well as the organizations Unions for the Performing Arts and the New York City Coalition for Economic Survival of Entertainment and the Arts.
  - Cabaret Law, mid 1980s-late 1980s (Box 85)
  - Cabaret Law, late 1970s-early 1990s (Box 86)
  - Cabaret Law, 1984-1990 (Box 87)
  - Unions for the Performing Arts and the New York City Coalition for Economic Survival of Entertainment and the Arts, early 1980s-early 1990s (Box 87)
  - Unions for the Performing Arts and the New York City Coalition for Economic Survival of Entertainment and the Arts (includes audio cassettes of 1985 Legislative Conference and a VHS tape of a 1984 teleconference), early 1980s-early 1990s (Box 131)
  - Judy West (Public Relations Director) Files: Jazz Foundation and Ad Hoc Committee for New York City, 1980s (Box 88)
  - Judy West (Public Relations Director) Files (mostly relating to New York City legislature), early 1980s-2000 (Box 89)
  - Judy West (Public Relations Director) Files, early 1980s-2000 (Box 90)
- Series VIII: Show Files, 1960s-2004
  Series VIII: Show Files, 1960s-2004 consists of contracts, correspondence, and financial records of Broadway and off-Broadway shows.
  - Show Files: A-Y, mid 1980s-early 1990s (Box 90)
  - Show Files: A-Y, mid 1970s-1996 (Box 91)
  - Show Files: A, 1990s (Box 91)
  - Show Files: A-N, 1990s (Box 92)
  - Show Files: O-T, 1990s (Box 93)
  - Show Files: A-C, 1970s-1996 (Box 93)
  - Show Files: C-Z, 1970s-1996 (Box 94)
  - Show Files: A-S, 1980s-1995 (Box 95)
  - Show Files: S-Y, 1980s-1995 (Box 96)
  - Show Files: A-C, 1970s-1993 (Box 96)
  - Show Files: C-S, 1970s-1993 (Box 97)
  - Show Files: T-Y, 1970s-1993 (Box 98)
  - Show Files: A-K, 1990s (Box 98)
  - Show Files: K-T, 1990s (Box 99)
  - Show Files: T-W, 1990s (Box 100)
  - Show Files: A-S, 1970s-1995 (Box 100)
  - Show Files: A-T, 1960s-1980s (Box 101)
  - Show Files: A-T, 1970s-1991 (Box 102)
  - League of American Theatres and Producers Grievances and Arbitrations, 1980s (Box 102)
  - Show Files: A-W, mid 1980s-early 1990s (Box 103)
  - Show Files: A-B, 1980s-2004 (Box 103)
  - Show Files: B-F, 1980s-2004 (Box 104)
  - Show Files: G-P, 1980s-2004 (Box 105)
  - Show Files: P-Y, 1980s-2004 (Box 106)
  - Subject Files: B-W, 1987-2001 (Box 106)
  - Show Files: B, 1970s-1980s (Box 106)
  - Show Files: B-W, 1970s-1980s (Box 107)
- Series IX: Trial Board Files, 1922-1990s
  Series IX: Trial Board Files, 1922-1990s consists primarily of the minutes of Trial Board hearings. The microfilm version of the minutes from 1921-1966 must be used.
  - Minutes, 1922-Jan 1923 (Film R-7438, Reel 50)
  - Minutes, Jan 1923-Oct 1924 (Film R-7438, Reel 51)
  - Minutes, Oct 1924-Apr 1926 (Film R-7438, Reel 52)
  - Minutes, Apr 1926-Sep 1927 (Film R-7438, Reel 53)
  - Minutes, Sep 1927-Jan 1929 (Film R-7438, Reel 54)
    Originals in Box 108 (Researchers must use microfilm)
  - Minutes, 1929-1930 (Film R-7438, Reel 55)
  - Minutes, 1931-1932 (Film R-7438, Reel 56)
  - Minutes, Jan 1933-Jun 1934 (Film R-7438, Reel 57)
  - Minutes, Jul 1934-1935 (Film R-7438, Reel 58)
  - Minutes, Jan 1936-Jun 1937 (Film R-7438, Reel 59)
  - Minutes, Jul 1937-Nov 1938 (Film R-7438, Reel 60)
  - Minutes, Nov 1938-Aug 1939 (Film R-7438, Reel 61)
  - Minutes, Aug 1939-1940 (Film R-7438, Reel 62)
  - Minutes, 1941 (Film R-7438, Reel 63)
  - Minutes, Jan 1942-Jun 1943 (Film R-7438, Reel 64)
  - Minutes, Jul 1943-1944 (Film R-7438, Reel 65)
  - Minutes, 1945-1946 (Film R-7438, Reel 66)
  - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Film R-7438, Reel 67)
  - Minutes, 1949 (Film R-7438, Reel 68)
  - Minutes, 1950-1951 (Film R-7438, Reel 69)
  - Minutes, 1952-1953 (Film R-7438, Reel 70)
  - Minutes, 1954-1955 (Film R-7438, Reel 71)
  - Minutes, 1956-1957 (Film R-7438, Reel 72)
  - Minutes, 1958-1959 (Film R-7438, Reel 73)
  - Minutes, Jan 1960-Jun 1961 (Film R-7438, Reel 74)
  - Minutes, Jul 1961-Apr 1962 (Film R-7438, Reel 75)
  - Minutes, Apr 1962-Aug 1963 (Film R-7438, Reel 76)
  - Minutes, Aug 1963-1964 (Film R-7438, Reel 77)
  - Minutes, 1965-1966 (Film R-7438, Reel 78)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 108)
  - Cases, Minutes, and Related Material, 1980s-1990s (Box 108)
  - Cases, Minutes, and Related Material, 1960s-1990s (Box 109)
  - Cases, Minutes, and Related Material, 1975-1977 (Box 110)
  - Cases, Minutes, and Related Material, 1978-1979 (Box 111)
  - Audio Cassette Recording of Trial Board Hearings, 1980s-1990s (Box 112)
  - Cases, Minutes, and Related Material, 1980 (Box 113)
  - Meeting Attendance Book, 1938-1941 (Box 119)
  - Meeting Attendance Book, 1982-1986 (Box 129)
- Series X: Oversized Material, 1921-1990s (Box 121, Box 120)
  Series X: Oversized Material, 1921-1990s includes several scrapbooks from the 1930s and 1940s, as well as the founding membership ledger of the local. The ledger must be viewed on microfilm.
  - American Federation of Musicians Convention, Las Vegas: Group Photo of Attendees, 1995 (Box Shared Tamiment C001)
  - Senior Musicians Association: Practice Photos (contact print), 1991 (Box Shared Tamiment C001)
  - William Feinberg (Secretary) Scrapbook of Correspondence and Ephemera (RESTRICTED: FRAGILE), 1939-1946 (Box 116)
  - Clippings Scrapbook Covering the Picketing of Movie Theatres that Play "Canned Music" (RESTRICTED: FRAGILE), Sep 1936-Dec 1936 (Box 116)
  - Clippings Scrapbook (RESTRICTED: FRAGILE), 1935-1946 (Box 117)
  - Leaves from Clippings Scrapbook (RESTRICTED: FRAGILE), circa 1940-1944 (Box 117)
  - Founding Membership Ledger: A-L, 1921-1924 (Film R-7886, Reel 1)
    Original in Box 120 (Researchers must use microfilm)
  - Founding Membership Ledger: M-Z, 1921-1924 (Film R-7886, Reel 2)
    Original in Box 121 (Researchers must use microfilm)
- Series XI: Photographs, undated
  Series XI: Photographs, undated contains approximately ten black and white publicity photographs of Local 802 performers.
  - Publicity Photographs, undated (Box Shared Tamiment A005)
- Series XII: Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 13 websites in 13 archived websites.
  This series contains the websites related to American Federation of Musicians, Local 802 and its organizing units, specifically the Musicians of the New York City Ballet and the Musicians of the New York Philharmonic. These website mostly focus on contract negotiations. The series also contains websites related to hardship fundraising for membership, especially during the COVID-19 pandemic. Other campaigns include digital rights and streaming and film residuals for union members.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Instagram feed was captured, but does not playback in Wayback.
  Accruals
  https://www.local802afm.org/ and https://www.instagram.com/musicians_of_ny/ are accrued quarterly. https://erf.local802afm.org/, https://afmfairshareformusicians.org/, https://musiciansofnycb.com/, and https://nypmusicians.org/ are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of local802afm.org, musicianscook.com, fairshareformusicians.org, savenycmusicians.com, musiciansofnycb.com, afmfairshareformusicians.org, and nypmusicians.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner.
  YouTube channels were added to captured embedded videos.
  Arrangement
  The series is in arranged chronologically by capture date.
  - American Federation of Musicans, Local 802, September 2007-ongoing
    Scope and Contents
    The website contains agreements and contracts, their Allegro magazine and other news postings, and event listings. The YouTube channel includes videos related to musician support during the COVID-19 pandemic, pension and insurance campaigns, the DCINY Orchestra Musicians strike, and the contract campaign Musicians of the New York City Ballet. The Instagram feed contains posts on Local events, contract campaigns, and solidarity actions with other unions.
  - Musicians' Emergency Relief Fund, May 2020-ongoing
    Historical Note
    The Musicians' Emergency Relief Fund is a fund for members of the American Federation of Musicians, Local 802. In 2020, the fund focused on raising funds for musicians affected by the COVID-19 pandemic.
    The website contains assistance applications, board of trustees and supporter information, initiatives and event information that fund raise for the fund, information on services to support member musicians, and testimonials from fund recipients.
  - Save NYC Musicians, December 2020-July 2024
    Save NYC Musicians was a campaign created by the American Federation of Musicians, Local 802 to fund raise for musicians and other artists who lost work due to COVID-19 pandemic. The proceeds of the fundraiser went to the Musicians' Emergency Relief Fund.
    The websites contained testimonials by public figures and union members, images, videos, and the Musicians Cook! campaign and book to raise funds for the Health Benefits plan.
  - Artists Rights Caucus, February 2023
    The Artists Rights Caucus (ARC) is a caucus of American Federation of Musicians Local 802 that advocates for legislative change to protect union members' digital rights and livelihoods. ARC supported a union campaign based on the the Music Community Response to the US Copyright Office Inquiry on Section 512 of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. The website was active in 2018 during the Local 802 union elections. Marc Ribot led the caucus.
  - Fair Share for Musicians, August 2023-ongoing
    Fair Share for Musicians is an action campaign of the American Federation of Musicians, Local 802 and Local 47 to demand a fair contract with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers Association that includes streaming film and television residuals for union members.
    The website contains a petition, news for the campaign, and information on solidarity with the 2023 Writers Guild of America and SAG-AFTRA strike. The website also includes 2024 contract bargaining updates from the union.
  - Musicians of the New York City Ballet, September 2023-ongoing
    Musicians of the New York City Ballet is a unit of the American Federation of Musicians Local 802, which represents the orchestra of the New York City Ballet.
    The websites contain a history of the orchestra, orchestra members, a discography of the orchestra, campaigns related to women's history in the orchestra, press, videos, and the 2023 contract campaign between management and musicians. The websites also include a petition for a fair contract that expired in August 2023.
  - Musicians of the New York Philharmonic, September 2024-ongoing
    The Musicians of the New York Philharmonic is a Local 802 unit and performer-led organization that represents members of the orchestra at the institution. In September 2024, the NY Philharmonic musicians settled on a collective bargaining agreement, which includes a 30 percent raise over three years.
    The website contains information about the performers and a call for support during the negotiation of the new contract.